MD HEDAYETUL ISLAM CHY

+8801829353906 \$ Chandgaon, Chittagong, Bangladesh islamhedayet67@gmail.com \$ hedayet13.github.io

I am an electrical engineer with a specialization in embedded systems, bio-surface modeling, medical image processing and coding. Currently, I'm fully captivating in the field of robotics and Biomedical Engineering, where i harness my expertise to drive innovation and make positive impact.

ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS

Master of Electrical and Electronic Engineering, University of Chittagong Bachelor of Electrical and Electronic Engineering, University of Chittagong Expected 2023 2017 - 2021

CGPA: 3.36

WORK EXPERIENCE

UprintBD, R&D Engineer

July 2022 - on going

 Reconfigured printing devices and developed a mobile app service alongside web server for accelerating cloud printing services.

THESIS AND PROJECT

Surface Engineering

Nov 2021 - June 2023

- Designed 3D printed surfaces to reduce fluid splashing and investigated simulations through Ansys Fluent.
- Applying different CFD methods such as Volume of Fluid, Eulerian method etc.
- Gathered data by designing 3D surface models to characterize the properties of different materials, namely PDMS, resin, and plastic.

Covid-19 ICU Monitoring

Aug 2020 - Mar 2021

- A system that assists hospital personnel in real-time monitoring of patients' bedside displays from a non-covid space. Experienced how a project becomes a product.
- Used light weight Flask framework with Nginx reverse proxy server on a Raspberry pi.
- Esp-32 camera for capturing image and send using TCP/IP protocol.
- Developed a Python Wrapper for conducting image processing and character recognition algorithms.
- Devised an cross-platform application that maintain communication with server.

AWARD AND TRAINING

- ICT Division Fellowship, awarded by Government of the People's Republic of Bangladesh, Bangladesh to support research in the field of bio-surface, 2023
- Former trainee, Ghorashal Training Center, Bangladesh Power Development Board, Palash, Narsingdi, 2021
- One of the top three team selected for National Hackathon 2019, Title: AI and ML recognized stereo camera for Occupational Health and Safety

SKILLS

Electrical & Mechanical PSpice, Proteus, Diptrace, Solidworks3D, Ansys Fluent, Strength analysis

Coding Python, MATLAB, Javascript, dart Linux UbuntuOS, KaliOS, Raspbian

Web server Flask, Django, Nodejs

Editting tools Illustrator, PremierePro, Photoshop, etc.

Others Flutter, Arduino, Raspberry pi, Machine Learning, Deep Learning,

Microsoft Azure services, Virtual machine, GCP, Docker, Etc.